<ootb-template>
<template-metadata name="block_voip_on_wan_link">
<template-details>
<description> In some cases, an administrator may want to force IP phones into SRST mode when a failover to a backup WAN link occurs. Implementing this blocking avoids transmitting voice over a lossy link, and it decreases the cost of a failure by reducing data usage while maintaining the dial tone that end-users expect. This configuration can be applied to the backup router of a dual router design or to the secondary link of a single router design. This configuration can also be used on any WAN interface when centralized voice registrations are not wanted at a particular remote site.!!! Usage: clean
</description>
<author>root</author><tag-list />
</template-details>
<parameter-metadata>
<param-group cliName="identity" isMandatory="true" name="Identity Commands">
<description>Parameters for aname</description>
<parameter name="interface_to_block">
<description>WAN interface to which the administrator wishes to block voice traffic.</description>
<html-component>textbox</html-component>
<default-value label="" />
<data-type>String</data-type>
<mandatory>false</mandatory>
<isGlobal>false</isGlobal>
<help-description />
<syntax>
<min />
<max />
<pattern>[^\s]*</pattern>
</syntax>
</parameter></param-group>
</parameter-metadata>
</template-metadata>
<config platform="IOS">
<device-filtering-details>
<family value="Switches">
<min-supported-imageversion value="IOS-XE" />
</family>
</device-filtering-details>
<cli name="identity">
<clicommand>!!! MACRO name block_voip_on_wan_link
!!! Platform: ISR2951, ISR2921, ISR2911, ISR3925, ISR3945, OS:
!!! Preconditions:
!!! Desc: In some cases, an administrator may want to force IP phones into SRST mode when a failover to a backup WAN link occurs. Implementing this blocking avoids transmitting voice over a lossy link, and it decreases the cost of a failure by reducing data usage while maintaining the dial tone that end-users expect. This configuration can be applied to the backup router of a dual router design or to the secondary link of a single router design. This configuration can also be used on any WAN interface when centralized voice registrations are not wanted at a particular remote site.
!!! Usage: clean
!!! Tags: voice, cucm, voip, sip, sccp, acl
!!! Vars: Only use "_" special characters in variable names
!!! $interface_to_block: ; WAN interface to which the administrator wishes to block voice traffic.

ip access-list extended ACL-VOIP-CONTROL 
  deny tcp any any eq 5060
  deny udp any any eq 5060
  deny tcp any any eq 5061
  deny udp any any eq 5061
  deny tcp any any eq 2000
  deny tcp any any eq 2443
  deny udp any any range 16384 32767 
  permit ip any any

interface $interface_to_block
!!interface interface_to_block
  ip access-group ACL-VOIP-CONTROL in
</clicommand>
</cli>
</config>
</ootb-template>